That day,
humanity was suddenly reminded...
of the terror of being at their mercy,
of the humiliation
of being trapped inside a cage.
All soldiers, prepare for battle!
We have one target!
We will slay it and claim this area
as humanity's first stronghold
beyond the walls!
Target approaching!
Split into five groups,
just as we practiced!
We'll act as the bait!
All assault squads,
switch to omnidirectional gear!
Strike from all directions at once!
Feel the power
of humanity!
What? Mikasa...
We should be getting back.
What are we doing here?
You must have been sleeping deeply
if you still haven't come to your senses.
No.
It just feels like I had this
really long dream or something.
What was it about?
I can't remember.
Eren, why are you crying?
What?
SHIGANSHINA DISTRICT, YEAR 845
Listen!
It was by God's great wisdom
that the walls were built!
The walls are His divine work!
No one must be allowed
to defile the walls!
Don't you dare tell anyone I was crying.
I won't.
Still, crying for no real reason...
You should have your dad
give you a checkup.
Don't be stupid! I can't tell him!
What were you crying about, Eren?
Mr. Hannes...
Did Mikasa nag you about something?
What makes you think I was crying?
Whoa, you reek of alcohol!
It's like... Come on, you know?
You're drinking again.
Do you guys want to join in?
Actually... Don't you have work?
Yes! We're guarding the gate today!
We were stuck here all day,
so we ended up getting hungry and thirsty.
If some booze happens to get into
our drinks, so what? It's no big deal.
What if something happens?
Can you fight like that?
- What do you mean, "if something happens"?
- You know what I mean!
I'm talking about if they break the walls
and get into the city!
It hurts.
Jeez, Eren. Don't go yelling like that.
The doctor's son has some spunk!
If they do bust down the walls,
we'll take care of business. Don't worry.
But that hasn't happened even once
in the last hundred years.
My dad says
there's nothing more dangerous
than being complacent!
Dr. Jaeger?
Yes, he's got a point.
He once saved this town from an epidemic.
I can't argue with him.
Still, they're different stories
altogether.
When you're a soldier, you get to see
those things roaming around outside
while you're on
wall reinforcement duty and stuff.
These walls are 50m tall, though.
I can't imagine them getting through.
Then, you're not actually
prepared to fight them at all?
No!
What?
Then drop the "Garrison Regiment" name
and use "Wall Construction Squad" instead!
That's not a bad idea!
But you have to understand, Eren.
If a soldier is doing his job, that means
things have seriously gone to hell.
It's better when everyone's
calling us useless freeloaders.
It means peaceful times for us all.
Sure, we can stay
inside the walls our entire lives
and do nothing but eat and sleep!
But that basically...
that basically makes us cattle!
Man, you're one plucky kid, all right!
For someone who's totally helpless!
Right, Hannes?
What? Yes.
Hey, Eren!
What a weirdo!
Wait. Don't tell me
he wants to join the Scout Regiment?
Eren, I'd forget about joining
the Scout Regiment if I were you.
What? You think the Scout Regiment
is a joke too?
It's not about what I think.
The Scout Regiment is back!
They're going to open the front gate!
Let's go and see
the heroes return, Mikasa!
Damn! I can't see!
They're the only ones who made it back?
Everyone else must have gotten eaten.
That's what they get
for going outside the walls.
Moses!
Excuse me.
I don't see my son, Moses, anywhere.
Do you know where he is?
This is Moses' mother.
Go and get it.
It's all we could retrieve.
But my son...
He was helpful, yes?
Even if he didn't achieve
anything directly,
surely my son's death
helped humanity fight back, yes?
Of course!
No.
During this latest scouting mission, we...
Just like all the other missions,
we didn't achieve anything at all!
My incompetence has done nothing
but needlessly send
soldiers to their deaths!
We haven't found out anything about them!
Talk about gruesome.
You can say that again.
Our taxes are basically going to
fatten those things up now.
What the hell, you little punk?
Hey! What are you doing, Mikasa?
Hey! Get back here!
Mikasa! Enough already!
What's the big idea?
Now the firewood's all over the place!
Eren.
Have you changed your mind
about joining the Scout Regiment?
Help pick this up.
It's not that bad of a mess.
We're home.
Welcome back.
Wow, Eren! You actually worked hard!
Yes.
What do you want?
Your ear's red. That shows you're lying.
You had Mikasa help you, didn't you?
You're leaving, Dad?
Is it for work?
Yes. Some checkups in the interior.
It will take a couple of days.
Eren says he wants to join
the Scout Regiment.
Mikasa! I told you not to say anything!
Eren!
What are you thinking?
Do you have any idea how many people
have died outside the walls?
- Yes, I know!
- Then--
Eren.
Why do you want to go out there?
I want to know
what the outside world is like!
I don't want to live my entire life
in ignorance inside the walls!
Plus,
if no one else is willing
to take their place,
then everyone's deaths
will have been in vain!
I see.
My boat's about to leave.
I better get going.
Hold on, dear! Talk some sense into Eren!
Carla.
Words can't hold back human curiosity.
Eren.
When I get back,
I'll show you the basement
that I've kept secret all this time.
Really?
Take care!
Just forget it.
Joining the Scout Regiment
is a stupid idea!
What? Stupid?
People who don't mind living
like livestock are the stupid ones!
Eren!
Mikasa.
He gets himself into trouble so easily.
If anything happens,
you need to be there for each other!
Yes.
What's the matter, you heretic?
If you don't like it, hit back!
As if!
That would be stooping to your level!
Say what?
You know I'm right!
That's why you resort to violence!
Because you can't argue back!
Which means you concede to me, doesn't it?
Shut up, smart-ass!
Stop that!
It's Eren!
- That idiot's back for more?
- Does he want his ass kicked?
We'll tear you a new one!
Mikasa's with him!
Screw this! Let's get out of here!
Just one look at me and they ran off!
No, it was Mikasa they saw.
Hey! You okay, Armin?
I can get up on my own.
I see.
I said humanity needs to venture
into the outside world at some point,
but then they beat me up
and called me a heretic.
Damn.
Why does everyone look down on people
who want to go outside?
Well, it's because
we've had a hundred years of peace
by staying inside the walls.
They're worried
that going outside carelessly
will invite them inside the walls.
The Royal Government's policies have made
having any interest
in the outside world a taboo.
It's our lives!
We can risk them if we want!
Absolutely not.
Forget about it.
Which reminds me,
I can't believe you told my parents!
What?
I never agreed to help.
So, what did they say?
They're less than pleased.
Figures.
Indeed, I think people are crazy
if they think we'll be
safe inside these walls forever.
Just because the walls
haven't fallen for a hundred years,
it doesn't guarantee
that they won't fall today.
And yet...
What was that?
An explosion?
- That way!
- Did something fall?
I'm not really sure.
Hey, Armin!
What is it? What do you see?
It can't be.
That wall is 50m high!
It's one of them.
A Titan!
It made a hole in the wall.
They're inside!
The Titans have gotten inside!
We need to run too!
Eren!
My house is in that direction.
Mom!
Mikasa!
It's all over.
Countless Titans are going to
overrun the city!
It couldn't have hit our home!
Just around this corner,
our house will stand there, like always!
Mom!
- Eren!
- Mikasa! Grab that end!
We have to move this pillar!
Hurry, Mikasa!
I know!
The Titans have gotten inside,
haven't they?
Eren! Take Mikasa and run away!
Hurry!
I want to!
So hurry up and get out of there!
The debris has crushed my legs.
Even if I could get out,
I wouldn't be able to run.
- You know what that means.
- I'll carry you, then!
Why don't you ever listen to your mother?
You can at least do this one last thing!
Mikasa!
No...
No!
If you don't go, all three of us will...
Hannes!
Take the children and get out of here!
Don't underestimate me, Carla.
I'm going to slaughter these Titans
and save all three of you!
Wait! Don't fight them!
Yes, I could save those two for sure.
But now,
I'm finally going to repay
the favor I owe!
Hey! Mr. Hannes!
What are you doing?
- Thank you.
- Hey!
Mom's still...
Eren! Mikasa!
You have to survive!
Don't go...
Stop!
That day,
humanity was suddenly reminded...
of the terror of being at their mercy,
of the humiliation
of being trapped inside a cage.
Shiganshina falls.
Humanity is only allowed
prayers, screams, and death.
Amid this, Eren alone
swears revenge in his small heart.